Srinivasa Chanakya Muramshetti

Lubbock, TX | smuramshetti@gmail.com | Cell:-8067020103 | LinkedIn | Portfolio

PROFILE

Around **3.5 years** of professional IT experience involving project development, implementation, deployment and maintenance using a strong foundation in coding, development, algorithms, and code architecture. My passion lies in breaking down complex problems into manageable components and collaborating with others to find creative solutions. With experience in coding, development, and data analysis, I am dedicated to applying my skills and knowledge to real-world problems and help clients to achieve their goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web developer

August 2022 - May 2023

Texas Tech university, TX, USA

- Developed and maintained **10+** web applications using **JavaScript, CSS, HTML** with back-end functionality implemented in **Python, C**, and **C++**.
- Utilized Python frameworks such as Django and Flask to build robust and scalable web applications, streamlining development processes and improving efficiency.
- Improved website page load speeds by **50%** by optimizing images, minifying code, and reducing server response time including image compression algorithms implemented in **Python**, code minification in **C++**, and optimizing server response time using C.
- Reviewed and monitored internal data processes, resulting in a 50% reduction in data errors.

Software Developer

August 2019 - November 2021

Kantar GDC, TG, India

- Productivity increased by 40% by developing and modifying the existing code, implemented in C# and Visual basic.
- Performed advance analytics in MS SQL and generated 30+ multi-grid tables for business intelligence.
- Collaborated with 7 team members in developing UI system built in ASP.NET frameworks.
- Involved in 100+ code reviews in multiple projects and found more reliable solutions than existing ones.
- Demonstrated expertise in developing robust and scalable solutions that meet business requirements while ensuring high performance and availability.

Quality Analyst

January 2019 - August 2019

Venkusa Technologies, TG, India

- Performed software application analysis to ensure the enterprise applications are good for production.
- Scripted more than 30+ automation scripts to improve the productivity and documented the same in welldesigned TDD format.

SKILLS

Scripting languages:- C, C++, Python, java, C#, VB.net, GoLang

Web technologies:- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, APEX

Data base:- MS SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Cloud Technologies:- AWS

Frame works and tools:- Angular, React.js, Node.js

Build tools:- Git, Docker, Ansible, Bitbucket

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University, TX

May 2023

Master of Computer Science

Malla Reddy Engineering College, Hyderabad

May 2019

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Developed a **meta-data** script that reduced the time needed to do repetitive operations, increasing employee productivity by **40%**.
- Received many Associate Contribution Excellence (ACE) Awards for solving critical issues and coming up with solutions/workarounds to cut down monetary loss incurred to client.